27, rue de la longue haie, 1630 LINKEBEEK, Belgium, Tel: +32 04 86 82 84 28

E-mail: queleanalytics@gmail.com, URL: https://be.linkedin.com/in/mauriceteko

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

With a strong problem-solving ability and statistical back ground i can Manage a team of data scientists, machine learning engineers and big data specialists. Leading data mining and collection procedures is a habit. I am open mind about how to contribute to the analytics scale up. The scope of data science is a blessing and a curse: it's not always clear how the team should direct its efforts to create the most value for the organization. Data science can improve customer-facing products and business decisions — and each of these areas are incredibly broad. It's a leader's job to keep an open mind about opportunities to contribute while maintaining enough focus for the team to be productive.

SKILLS

Applications: C/C++, Camel, Scilab, Latex, TEX

Programming: R, Python, H2O, Tensorflow, ELK Stack

Statistics: Bayesian models, frequentist statistics, Machine learning, Deep learning, . . .

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF LIEGE PhD Candidate, Statistics (2010)

Thesis in preparation

UNIVERSITY OF STRASBOURG Master of Mathematics & Statistics, Statistics (2006)

Thesis in the area of Statistics

UNIVERSITY OF STRASBOURG Licence in Mathematics, Mathematics & Statistics (2004)

Thesis in the area of Mathematics

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

QUELEANALYTICS, linkebeek, Belgium

Consultant Leading digital transformation/ Lead Data Scientist (November 2019 - Present) Planning data projects. Building analytic systems and predictive models. Managing a team of data scientists, machine learning engineers and big data specialists.

TOURING ASSURANCES, Bruxelles, Belgium

Senior Data Scientist (September 2018 - November 2019)

Planning data projects. Building predictive models (lapses models, customer life time value,...).

AGINSURANCES, Bruxelles, Belgium

Data Scientist (June 2015 - September 2018)

Collaborating filtering, Text mining, People(HR) Analytics, Next best buy. Propensity to buy modeling. Bayesian modeling. Data modeling, data processing and transformation: from supervised approaches to unsupervised.

4CLINICS, BELGIUM, Bruxelles, Belgium

Statistician (January 2007 - June 2015)

Study analysis plan writing, analyses. writing of the statisticals reports and its conclusions, review of the clinical study report and the clinical trial register sumlmary. Studies on Flu pandemic, Tuberculosis, Dengue Tetravalent,...

OUTSIDE WORK ACCOMPLISHMENTS

REFEREES